Resume of Victor Kachan (Web developer, Java developer)

Personal details

Contact information

Name Victor Kachan E-mail setec.by@gmail.com

Date of birth 28 Aug 1982 Skype viktar.kachan

Nationality Belarus Phone +375—33—6645731

Languages Russian, English

Web version of resume http://stq.github.io

Education

2004-2005 Java Training Course at BSUIR/EPAM Joint Lab

2000-2005 Bachelor in Informatics (Mathematician, System programmer) at BSUIR(Minsk, Belarus)

Career summary

- •Got over 10 years of practical experience with commercial web applications.
- •Focused on web development technologies.
- •Have major experience with back-end server frameworks and technologies (Java EE and others).

Main technology skills

Web/Markup: HTML, CSS

Web/Markup/Graphics: SVG, VML, HTML5 Canvas, WebGL, etc.*

Web/Scripting: Javascript, Angular, etc.*

Java/Core: Java SE7 (Language, Concepts, API)

Java EE/Web: Servlet API, Spring MVC, Struts, Portlet API Java EE/Web/Markup: JSP/EL/JSTL, Freemarker, Stripes, Wicket, Tiles

Java EE/Spring: Core (DI,AOP), Data(Transactions,ORM)**, Web(MVC, REST)

Java EE/Backend: Java EE API (DI, JSF, JAX-WS/RS, EJB, JMS, JPA, JTA)**, ORM (Hibernate)**

Database: RDBMS(SQL, PL/SQL)**, NoSQL**

Other: Computer graphics, Applied math, Applied semantics, Web streaming**

<u>Technology experience overview</u> (detailed interactive version available at http://stq.github.io)



^{*} see career and skills for details

^{**} not a focus area

Career (interactive version is available at http://stq.github.io)

At R-Style Lab

from Jan, 2014 to Jan, 2015, totally 1 year

Mar -2014- eGov.kz v2

Jan–2015 A web portal and kiosk-mode web app designed to provide a variety of governmental services to individual

9 month and organizations.

Position: Frontend Architect Achievement:

Participation: Development and support of toolchain, frameworks, web Suggested development

components. Team/PM assistance. methodologies which gave major

boost on development performance.

Skills: Javascript (Angular, Lodash), Node.js (Express, Walk), HTML/CSS

Team size: 38

Jan-2014 - eGov.kz v2 prototype

Apr-2014 Development of UI architecture and functionality.

4 month Position: Lead web developer Achievement:

Participation: Development of UI architecture and functionality. Separated frontend from java devs

so they could't ruin development

Major boost on web skills. Getting

performance.

Skills: Javascript (Angular, Lodash), Node.js (Express, Walk), HTML/CSS

Team size: 3

At **Fitbit**

from December, 2012 to December, 2013, totally 1 year and 1 month

Dec-2012 - Fitbit Corporate Wellness

Dec-2013 Web application for monitoring corporate personnel physical activity.

1 year and Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

1 month Participation: Development, support, improvement of charts

functionality. Development and support of various web over highcharts limits. Advanced widgets. Development of OAuth authentication flow.

Agile methodology experience.

Skills: Javascript (jQuery, Backbone, Underscore, Highcharts), HTML/CSS, SVG, VML, Raphael, JSP/EL/JSTL, Java, Spring (DI, MVC,

REST), Stripes, Guava, Java EE(Servlets, JMS), ORM (Hibernate), NoSQL (Cassandra)

Team size: 10-15

At Logic Way

from May, 2010 to November, 2012, totally 2 years and 7 months

Aug-2012 - Customs Management application

Nov-2012 Web client to manage customs database entities, made on base of existing Delphi application.

4 months Position: Lead developer Achievement:

Participation: Architecture development and support, base

Automatic DFM form to HTML layout

components development, team coordination. conversion.

Skills: Java, Wicket, HTML/CSS, Spring (DI, ORM), SQL, ORM (Hibernate), Javascript(jQuery), Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 3-10

Jul-2012 - <u>Car insurance agency web services</u>

Jul–2012 Set of web services under Russian Car Insurance Association to be used by local agencies.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Development of MQ manager and web services.

Skills: Java, Spring (DI), PL/SQL

Team size: 10-15

Jun-2012 - <u>CeConvergence</u>

Jun-2012 Web application for tracking and notification of accountant training courses.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Development of various features.

Skills: Java, Spring (MVC, DI), PL/SQL

Team size: 5

May–2012 – YouTube downloader

May-2012 Software which allows downloading youtube videos.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Research, development. Skills: Java, YouTube API, FLV, Video encoding

Team size: 1

Feb-2012 - Mind.com webinars

Apr-2012 Online webinars system.

3 months Position: Java developer, Web developer

Participation: Development of various features and improvements.

Skills: Java, HTML/CSS, SVG, VML, RaphaelGWT, Raphael, Guava, Hibernate, Apache Batic, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 8

Sep-2011 - Whiteboard module for Mind.com webinars

Jan-2012

Whiteboard module for sharing drawings, images and documents at web video conference system.

5 months

Position: Lead developer, Team management Achievement:

Participation: Technology assistance, project management,

Project management skills, SVG

development. *experience*.

Skills: Java, HTML/CSS, SVG, VML, RaphaelGWT, Raphael, Guava, ORM (Hibernate), Apache Batic, Javascript (jQuery), JavaEE (Servlets)

Team size: 3

Aug-2011 - Automated fine payment system

Aug-2011

Module for fine payment in customs control application.

1 month

Position: SQL developer

Participation: Development of PL/SQL services.

Skills: PL/SQL Team size: 1

Jun-2011 - PeopleNet logistics tracking

Jul-2011 Web application which provide different services for logistics — tracking, optimization.

2 months Position: Contractor, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Web service development. Contractor experience, GWT experience.

Skills: Java, SQL, OSCi, ORM (Hibernate), Spring (DI, ORM), GWT, Ext GWT, Portlets, Java EE(Servlets, EJB)

Team size: 20-30

Dec-2010 -**Severstal ESK Contractor Management System**

May-2011 6 months

Web client application for contractors browsing and management (variety of specific business domain actions).

Position: Java developer, Team lead

Achievement:

Participation: Portal server maintenance, portlet implementation Helped customer to fix server failure

assistance, team training.

after midnight.

Skills: Java, XML/XSD, WSDL, Axis, IBM XML Beans, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Javascript(jQuery), Portlets, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 5-6

Jun-2010 -**MSC Council Archive**

Nov-2010

6 months

Web application to store, secure, manage, browse and share official documentation.

Position: SQL developer, Java developer, Web developer, Team lead

Achievement:

Made AOP-based

better performance.

data caching for

Participation: Development of UI BREAD engine and UI implementation. Frontend application DB/BL/Services development. Development of IBM ICM

interface utility (ICM operations interface, data

export/import/synchronization).

Skills: Java, XML/XSD, Freemarker, HTML/CSS, Javascript, SQL, IBM CM, Javassist, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 3

MSC Internal Affairs Archive May-2010 -

DB archive application to secure and manage official documentation. May-2010

1 month

Position: DB developer, Java developer

Achievement:

Participation: DB structure implementation and support. Development of database Good DB experience.

export/import utility.

Skills: Java, SQL, PL/SQL

Team size: 2

At Specific Group AG

from March, 2009 to April, 2010, totally 1 year and 2 months

Mar-2009 -**European Gate**

Apr-2010 Server application for format conversion of financial transaction. With web client for control/monitoring.

Position: Technical writer, Java developer, Web developer 1 year and

Achievement:

2 months

Participation: Project documentation, status feedback, code review, architecture

review. Consulting branch department. Introduction of CI process.

introduction. Multiple code Web client improvements, wicket model optimization. Conversion and process optimizations.

Documentation process

compatibility testing framework development.

Skills: ANTLR, UML, Java, Spring (DI, ORM), Wicket, HTML/CSS, ORM (Hibernate), Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 5-7

At **Agava**

from August, 2008 to November, 2008, totally 4 months

Sep-2008 -Rebot.ru web development

Nov-2008 News feed reader, which knows what news will be interesting to the user.

3 months Position: Web developer Achievement:

Participation: WSDL development, web frontend development, integration with

Agava CRM.

Boost on HTML/CSS skills.

Skills: Java, Javascript(jQuery), HTML/CSS, Java EE (Servlets, Web services), Axis, Axis WSF

Team size: 2-3

Aug-2008 - Adbroker.ru instant search

Aug-2008 Web advertisements management system: ads trade, management, control, statistics.

1 month Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Development of instant search.

Introduced minor performance

optimization on instant search.

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, EJB, Web services), ORM (Hibernate), SQL, JBoss Seam, Axis, Javascript(jQuery), HTML/CSS, XSLT

Team size: 1

At Generation-P consulting ltd.

from February, 2008 to June, 2008, totally 5 months

Feb-2008 - Web application for job surveys service

Jun-2008 Online survey for a big job agency. Featuring automatic survey management, analysis and report tools.

5 months Position: Consultant, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Architecture optimization: transaction safety, deadlocks, memory Successfully improved usage, performance, clustering. Performance and functional performance and stability

testing tools. Code review. EJB 2.0 upgrade to EJB 3.0. Spring of application.

integration.

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, JMS, EJB), ORM (Hibernate), SQL, Clustering (JOnAS), Spring (DI), JUnit

Team size: 4

At EPAM, Hyperion Department

from September, 2007 to January, 2008, totally 5 months

Sep-2007 - Hyperion Strategic Finance / Profitability module

Jan-2008 Web client software for development of financial plan.

5 months Position: Java developer, Web developer Achievement:

Participation: Module component development: UI, business logic, testing

and integration.

SE (C. 1. DAG EID IGE) ODM (T. 1.1.) COL D. 1

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, JMS, EJB, JSF), ORM (TopLink), SQL, Bindows

Team size: 15-20

At EPAM, Travel Solutions Department April, 2005 to August, 2007 - 2 years and 5 months

Oct-2006 - Travel Distribution Platform

Aug-2007 Platform for online booking web applications.

11 months Position: Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Design and development of booking services. Assisting with Good experience with web

integration. services.

Skills: UML, Java, Struts 1.x, JSP/EL/JSTL, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis)

Team size: 10-15

Got some Java EE experience.

Jan-2006 - Vail Resorts call center

Sep-2006 Web frontend with BREAD-functionality for reservation management service.

9 months Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Research and architecture on web communication layer. Introduction of custom model-

Development and support of custom BREAD MVC framework. view javascript framework.

Skills: Javascript, Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Jul-2005 - Scandinavian Airlines booking

Dec-2005 Web application for flight itinerary search and reservation. Have original design.

6 months Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Presentation layer and business logic implementation. Perfect teamwork, happy customer.

Skills: Javascript, DWR, Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Apr-2005 - South African Airways booking

Jun-2005 Web application for flight itinerary search and reservation.

3 months Position: Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Presentation layer and business logic implementation. Promoted JSP Tag unit tests.

Skills: Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Web version of my work profile:

Please visit my web site http://stq.github.io to see web version of this resume, which is more comfortable to read. To see source code, use this link: http://stq.github.io/index-full.html

With best regards, Victor Kachan (setec.by@gmail.com)

Last updated Dec, 2014